Preliminary Inventory to the John Doane Hartigan Papers, 1909-1958
Hoover Institution Archives
John Doane Hartigan Papers,
1909-1958
46014
Hartigan, John Doane, 1890-1959
33 manuscript boxes (13.8 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Correspondence, reports, memoranda, writings, pamphlets, clippings, photographs, and posters, relating to relief work during the two world wars, the Saar plebiscite of 1934-1935, the Allied government in Austria after World War II, and the organization of international trade fairs. Includes correspondence with Herbert Hoover.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Access Points
Hoover, Herbert, 1874-1964.; Fairs.; International economic relations.; International relief.; World War, 1914-1918.; World War, 1914-1918--Civilian relief.; World War, 1939-1945.; World War, 1939-1945--Civilian relief.; Austria.; Austria--History--Allied occupation, 1945-1955.; Germany.; Saarland (Germany); United States--Foreign relations.
Biography
American relief worker in Europe, 1919 and 1939-1941; member, Saar Plebiscite Commission, 1934-1935; member, United States Military Government in Austria, 1945-1946.
Container List
- Material relating to establishment of International Trade Commission; Flood Bill, no. 5301; and San Francisco World Trade Center Authority (Box 1.)
  - Names
    - Clark
    - Cutler (Chairman of San Francisco World Trade Center Authority, 1955)
    - Flood
    - Flood (Box 2.)
    - Hartigan
    - Hoover. See Box 5
    - Pennoyer
    - Strauss
    - Taft
    - Tuck
  - Subjects (Box 3.)
    - Miscellaneous correspondence
    - Correspondence, 1956 (Box 4.)
    - American publications information
    - Dickerson College, Carlisle, Pennsylvania
    - European and South America trips
    - U.S. government agencies
    - Republican National Committee
    - Stanford Research Institute
    - U.S. Department of Commerce
    - U.S. Department of State and White House
    - U.S. Senators
- Herbert Hoover (Box 5.)
  - Correspondence
  - Other personal correspondence
  - Signed letter of gratitude by Harry Truman re military service, 1949
  - Material re Herbert Hoover's trip to Europe, 1938
- Reports on U.S. and foreign universities, 1948-1950 (Box 6.)
- Military reports and career of John Doane Hartigan (Box 7.)
- Article by General Joseph W. Beacham with photographs of General McArthur and Dwight D. Eisenhower, 1949-1954
- U.S. military in America, 1945-1948
- Letters and sketches of U.S. military officer in Austria, 1945-1948
- John Doane Hartigan's army file, 1942-1946
- Foreign countries, agencies, and U.S. Embassy, 1950-1958 (Box 8.)
- Brussels International Fair, 1958
- Correspondence, mainly re Trade Fair
- Foreign countries, agencies, and U.S. Embassy (Box 9.)
- Correspondence, mainly re Trade Fair, 1934-1956
- Facts and figures re The Baar
- U.S. cities. Miscellaneous correspondence to people in the U.S., 1950-1958 (Box 10.)
- U.S. cities (Box 11.)
- U.S., Canada, and South America (Box 12.)
- Decorations (Box 13.)
- Army insignia, medals, and miscellaneous items of John Doane Hartigan (Box 14.)
- Photographs (Box 15-17.)
- Trade. Pamphlets, etc. (Box 18-19.)
- Trade - Brussels Fair, 1958 (Box 20.)
- Trade. Pamphlets, etc. (Box 21.)
- Galley, "The Musings of a Sidewalk Diplomat," by John Doane Hartigan (Box 22.)
- U.S. Department of Agriculture. Miscellaneous pamphlets re plants, fruit, etc., 1929-1933 (Box 23.)
- Newspapers (Box 24.)
- Provisional handbook for Military Government in Austria (restricted in 1945) (Box 25.)
- Miscellaneous printed matter and unsorted material (Box 26-33. & on shelf)
- Ballot box, Saar Plebiscite, 13 January 1935 (St. Ingbert, approximately 10 km east of Sarrebruck) (Box Above record cabinet)